The following are my opinions,
ما سوف يأتي هي أرائي،
and do not reflect the opinions or policies
وهي لا تعبر عن أراء أو سياسات
of any particular prosecutor's office.
أي مكتب إدعاء عام آخر.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I am a prosecutor.
أنا مدعٍ عام.
I believe in law and order.
أنا أؤمن بالقانون و النظام.
I am the adopted son of a police officer, a Marine and a hairdresser.
أنا ابن بالتبني لضابط شرطة في البحرية ومصففة شعر.
I believe in accountability
أنا أؤمن بالمساءلة
and that we should all be safe in our communities.
وأن نكون جميعا أمنين في مجتمعاتنا.
I love my job
أنا أحب عملي
and the people that do it.
ومن يقومون بمثله.
I just think that it's our responsibility
أنا أعتقد أنها مسؤليتنا
to do it better.
أن نعمل بشكل أفضل
By a show of hands,
برفع الأيدي،
how many of you, by the age of 25,
كم منكم في سن 25،
had either acted up in school,
قد أساء التصرف في المدرسة،
went somewhere you were specifically told to stay out of,
أو ذهب لمكان ما سبق وأن تم تحذيره منه،
or drank alcohol before your legal age?
أو شرب الكحول قبل السن القانوني؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
All right.
حسنا،
How many of you shoplifted,
كم شخص منكم سبق وسرق من متجر،
tried an illegal drug
أو جرب مخدرات غير قانونية
or got into a physical fight --
أو تعرض لمشاجرة بدنية--
yes, even with a sibling?
حتى لو مع شقيقه؟
Now, how many of you ever spent one day in jail
كم شخص منكم سبق وقضى يوما واحدا في السجن
for any of those decisions?
لأي سبب مما سبق؟
How many of you sitting here today
كم شخص منكم يجلس هنا اليوم
think that you're a danger to society
ويفكر بأنه خطر على المجتمع
or should be defined by those actions of youthful indiscretion?
أو يجب ان يتم تعريفه من حركاته وحماقاته الصبيانية؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Point taken.
لقد فهمت.
When we talk about criminal justice reform,
عندما نتحدث عن إصلاح العدالة الجنائية،
we often focus on a few things,
نحن غالبا نركز على أشياء قليلة،
and that's what I want to talk to you about today.
وهذا ما أريد أن آتحدث عنه اليوم.
But first I'm going to -- since you shared with me,
ولكن أولاً سوف -- بما أنكم نقاسمتم معي،
I'm going to give you a confession on my part.
سوف أعترف لكم ببعض الإعترافات.
I went to law school
ذهبت إلى كلية الحقوق
to make money.
لجني المال.
I had no interest in being a public servant,
لم يكن لدي اهتمام في أن أكون موظفا حكوميا،
I had no interest in criminal law,
أو اي اهتمام في القانون الجنائي،
and I definitely didn't think that I would ever be a prosecutor.
ولم أفكر قطعا في أن أكون مدعي عام.
Near the end of my first year of law school, I got an internship
قرب نهاية سنتي الأولى حصلت على فترة تدريب
in the Roxbury Division of Boston Municipal Court.
في حي راكسباري، محكمة بوسطن،
I knew of Roxbury as an impoverished neighborhood in Boston,
أنا أعرف أن راكسباري حى فقير فى بوسطن،
plagued by gun violence and drug crime.
وينتشر فيه العنف المسلح وجرائم المخدرات.
My life and my legal career changed the first day of that internship.
حياتي ومهنتي تغيرت في أول يوم تدريب.
I walked into a courtroom, and I saw an auditorium of people
مشيت لغرفة المحكمة، ورأيت قاعة مليئة بالناس
who, one by one, would approach the front of that courtroom
الذين يقفون واحد تلو الأخر في قاعة المحكمة
to say two words and two words only:
ليقولوا كلمتين فقط،
"Not guilty."
وهي "غير مذنب".
They were predominately black and brown.
وكانت أغلبيتهم ذوي بشرة سوداء وبنية
And then a judge, a defense attorney and a prosecutor
ومن ثم قاضٍ، ومحام، ومدعٍ عام
would make life-altering decisions about that person without their input.
يتخذون قرارات مصيرية بخصوص ذلك الشخص بدون مساهمته
They were predominately white.
وكان أغلبيتهم ذوي بشرة بيضاء.
As each person, one by one, approached the front of that courtroom,
بينما يقترب كل شخص واحدا تلو الآخر، أمام غرفة الجلسات،
I couldn't stop but think:
لم أستطع التوقف عن التفكير:
How did they get here?
كيف جاؤوا إلى هنا؟
I wanted to know their stories.
كنت أريد أن أعرف قصصهم.
And as the prosecutor read the facts of each case,
بحكم أنَّ المدعي العام يقرأ حقائق كل قضية،
I was thinking to myself,
كُنت أفكر في نفسي،
we could have predicted that.
كان باستطاعتنا أن تنبأ بذلك.
That seems so preventable...
كان يبدو بأننا قادرين على منعها...
not because I was an expert in criminal law,
ليس لأنّي كُنت خبيرا في القانون الجنائي،
but because it was common sense.
ولكن لأنّهُ كان التفكير السليم.
Over the course of the internship,
على مدى فترة التدريب،
I began to recognize people in the auditorium,
بدأت أتعرف على الناس في القاعة،
not because they were criminal masterminds
ليس لأنهم كانوا العقول المدبرة للجريمة
but because they were coming to us for help
ولكن لأنهم كانو يأتون لنا لطلب المساعدة
and we were sending them out without any.
ونتركهم دون مساعدة.
My second year of law school I worked as a paralegal for a defense attorney,
في السنة الثانية عملت كمساعد لمحام الدفاع،
and in that experience I met many young men accused of murder.
و في هذه التجربة قابلت كثيرًا من الشباب المتهمين بجرائم قتل.
Even in our "worst," I saw human stories.
و حتى في "أسوأ" الحالات رأيت قصص انسانية.
And they all contained childhood trauma,
وجميعها تحتوي على صدمات في مرحلة الطفولة،
victimization, poverty, loss,
الإيذاء، الفقر، الفقد،
disengagement from school,
الإنفصال من المدرسة،
early interaction with the police and the criminal justice system,
التفاعل المبكر مع الشرطه ونظام العدالة الجنائية،
all leading to a seat in a courtroom.
كلها تؤدي إلى المحكمة.
Those convicted of murder were condemned to die in prison,
أولئك الذين أدينوا بالقتل فقد حكم عليهم بالموت في السجن
and it was during those meetings with those men that I couldn't fathom
و خلال هذه الاجتماعات مع هؤلاء الرجال لم أكن أستوعب
why we would spend so much money
لماذا نُنْفق الكثير من المال
to keep this one person in jail for the next 80 years
لإبقاء إنسان في السجن ل 80 سنة المقبلة
when we could have reinvested it up front,
بينما كنا نستطيع أن نستثمره مسبقا،
and perhaps prevented the whole thing from happening in the first place.
ولكان بمقدورنا أن نمنع حصول الأمر كله من البداية
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
My third year of law school,
في سنتي الثالثة في كلية القانون،
I defended people accused of small street crimes,
دافعت عن أشخاص متهمين بجرائم شوارع صغيرة،
mostly mentally ill,
معظمهم مرضى عقليون،
mostly homeless,
معظمهم من المشردين،
mostly drug-addicted,
ومعظمهم من مدمني المخدرات
all in need of help.
كلهم بحاجة إلى المساعدة.
They would come to us,
كانوا يأتون إلينا،
and we would send them away without that help.
ولم نكُن نساعدهم.
They were in need of our assistance.
كانوا بحاجة إلى الإعانة،
But we weren't giving them any.
ولكننا لم نقدم لهم أي مساعدة.
Prosecuted, adjudged and defended
يُدَانُون ويُحكم عليهم و يدافع عنهم
by people who knew nothing about them.
من قبل أشخاص لا يعرفون أي شيء عنهم.
The staggering inefficiency is what drove me to criminal justice work.
عدم الكفاءة هي ما دفعتني للعمل في العدالة الجنائية
The unfairness of it all made me want to be a defender.
الظلم الجائر هو ما جعلني مدافعا.
The power dynamic that I came to understand
فهمي لديناميكا السلطة
made me become a prosecutor.
جعلتني أصبح مدعيا عاما.
we know there are 2.3 million people in American jails and prisons,
نحن نعلم أن هُناك 2.3 مليون شخص في سجون أمريكا،
making us the most incarcerated nation on the planet.
وهو ما يجعلنا أكثر أمة مسجونة على الكوكب.
We know there's another seven million people on probation or parole,
وهناك سبعة ملايين شخص تحت المراقبة أو السراح المشروط،
we know that the criminal justice system
نحن نعلم بأن نظام العدالة الجنائية
disproportionately affects people of color,
يؤثر على الناس ذوي البشرة الملونة بشكل متفاوت
particularly poor people of color.
وخصوصا الفقراء منهم.
And we know there are system failures happening everywhere
ونحن نعلم بأنه توجد أنظمة فاشلة في كل مكان
that bring people to our courtrooms.
وهي ما تجلب الناس لقاعات المحكمة.
But what we do not discuss
ولكن ما لا نُناقشه
is how ill-equipped our prosecutors are to receive them.
هو مدي سوء تجهيز المدعين لدينا لإستقبالهم.
When we talk about criminal justice reform,
عندما نتحدث عن إصلاح العدالة الجنائية،
we, as a society, focus on three things.
نحن نركز على ثلاثة أشياء.
We complain, we tweet, we protest
الشكوى و التغريد و الإحتجاج
about the police, about sentencing laws
من الشرطة والقوانين
and about prison.
والسجن.
We rarely, if ever, talk about the prosecutor.
نحن نادراً ما نتحدث عن المدعي العام.
In the fall of 2009,
في خريف ٢٠٠٩،
a young man was arrested by the Boston Police Department.
ألقي القبض على شاب من قبل شرطة بوسطن.
He was 18 years old, he was African American
عمره ١٨ سنة، وكان أمريكي من أصل أفريقي
and he was a senior at a local public school.
في سنته الأخيره من المدرسة.
He had his sights set on college
كان يُريد الدخول إلى الجامعة
but his part-time, minimum-wage job wasn't providing the financial opportunity
ولكن مَرْتَب دوامه الجزئي القليل لم يمكنه من الدخول
he needed to enroll in school.
واحتاج أن ينفصل من المدرسة.
In a series of bad decisions,
في سلسلة من القرارات السيئة،
he stole 30 laptops from a store and sold them on the Internet.
سرق ٣٠ من أجهزة الكمبيوتر المحمولة من محل وباعهم في الإنترنت.
This led to his arrest
ومن ثم أُعتقل
and a criminal complaint of 30 felony charges.
و حكم عليه بـ 30 تهمة جنائية
The potential jail time he faced is what stressed Christopher out the most.
وقت السجن المُتوقع هو ما أرهق كريستوفر.
But what he had little understanding of
لكن كريستوفر لم يكن يفهم تأثير سجله الإجرامي على مستقبله.
I was standing in arraignments that day
كُنت أقف في المحكمه ذلك اليوم
when Christopher's case came across my desk.
عندما أتت قضية كريستوفر لمكتبي.
And at the risk of sounding dramatic, in that moment,
وفي تلك اللحظة الدرامية،
I had Christopher's life in my hands.
كانت حياة كريستوفر بين يدي.
I was 29 years old, a brand-new prosecutor,
كنت مدعي عام ذا الـ ٢٩ عام
and I had little appreciation for how the decisions I would make
ولدي وعي للقرارات التي سوف أتخذها
would impact Christopher's life.
وهي سوف تؤثر على حياة كريستوفر.
Christopher's case was a serious one
قضية كريستوفر كانت قضيه جاده
and it needed to be dealt with as such,
ولابُد أن أكون حذر معها،
but I didn't think branding him a felon for the rest of his life
ولكن لم أستطع أن أصفه بالمجرم لبقية حياته
was the right answer.
بالأمر الصحيح
For the most part, prosecutors step onto the job
للأهميه فعمل المدعي العام يتضمن
with little appreciation of the impact of our decisions,
وعي لقراراته فهي مؤثره
regardless of our intent.
بغض النظر عن النية.
Despite our broad discretion,
رغم حريتنا في التصرف والقرار،
we learn to avoid risk at all cost,
تعلمنا أن نتجنب المخاطر بأي ثمن،
rendering our discretion
إعطائنا الحريه
basically useless.
في الأساس غير فعّال.
History has conditioned us to believe that somehow,
بطريقة أو بأخرى التاريخ عوّدنا أن نؤمن
the criminal justice system brings about accountability
بأنّ نظام العدالة الجنائية يجلب المسائله
and improves public safety,
ويُحسّن السلامه العامه،
despite evidence to the contrary.
رغم وجود أدلة على عكس ذلك.
so prosecutors aren't really incentivized to be creative
لذلك المدعون لايحفزون على الابداع
at our case dispositions,
عند التصرف في قضايانا،
or to take risks on people we might not otherwise.
لتحمل المخاطر على الناس قد لا نفعل غير ذلك
We stick to an outdated method,
نحن نتمسك باسلوب قديم،
counterproductive to achieving the very goal that we all want,
غير مثمر فى تحقيق الهدف نفسه الذى نريده جميعا،
and that's safer communities.
أن نكون مجتمع أمن.
Yet most prosecutors standing in my space would have arraigned Christopher.
معظم المدعيين إذا كانوا مكاني لقاموا بإستدعاء كريستوفر.
They have little appreciation for what we can do.
لديهم تقدير ضعيف لما نستطيع فعله
Arraigning Christopher would give him a criminal record,
إستدعاء كريستوفر سوف يعطيه سجل جنائي
making it harder for him to get a job,
مما يصعب حصوله على وظيفة
setting in motion a cycle
ويعيش في هذه الدورة
With a criminal record and without a job,
مع تاريخ إجرامي ومن دون وظيفه،
Christopher would be unable to find employment, education or stable housing.
كريستوفر لن يكون قادر على ايجاد فرصة عمل او تعليم او يستقر سكنيا
Without those protective factors in his life,
بدون هذه العوامل في حياته،
Christopher would be more likely to commit further, more serious crime.
كريستوفر سوف يستمر بإرتكاب الجرائم.
The more contact Christopher had with the criminal justice system,
كلما تواصل كريستوفر أكثر مع نظام العدالة
and again and again --
ومرة ​​أخرى
all at tremendous social cost to his children, to his family
وكلها بتكلفة اجتماعية هائلة على اطفاله وعلى اسرته
and to his peers.
وأقرانه كذلك.
And, ladies and gentlemen,
سيداتي وسادتي،
it is a terrible public safety outcome for the rest of us.
إنها نتيجة فظيعه لكُلٍّ منّا.
When I came out of law school,
عندنا تخرجت من كلية الحقوق،
I did the same thing as everybody else.
فعلت نفس الشيء كما أي شخص آخر.
I came out as a prosecutor expected to do justice,
خرجت في منصب المدعي العام الذي من المتوقع أن ينصف،
but I never learned what justice was in my classes --
ولكنّنِي لم أتعلم أبداً ماهي العدالة
none of us do.
ولم يتعلم أي أحد منّا.
None of us do.
ولا أحد.
And yet, prosecutors are the most powerful actors
ومع ذلك نحن أكثر ممثلين فعّالين
in the criminal justice system.
في نظام العداله الجنائيه،
Our power is virtually boundless.
سلطتنا عملياً غير محدوده.
In most cases, not the judge,
في معظم القضايا، ليس القاضي،
not the police, not the legislature,
ليست الشرطه، ولا من يُسن القوانين،
not the mayor, not the governor, not the President
ليس العمده ولا الحاكم ولا رئيس الجمهورية
can tell us how to prosecute our cases.
يستطيع أن يخبرنا كيف نتعامل مع قضايانا.
The decision to arraign Christopher and give him a criminal record
القرار باستدعاء كريستوفر وإدانته
was exclusively mine.
كان حصراً لي.
I would choose whether to prosecute him for 30 felonies, for one felony,
كان باستطاعتي الخيار بإدانته بـ 30 جريمة
for a misdemeanor,
أو جريمه واحده أقل وحشيه
or at all.
أو لا شيء.
I would choose whether to leverage Christopher into a plea deal
بإمكاني الوصول بـ كريستوف إلى اتفاق مع الادعاء
I would be in a position to ask for Christopher to go to jail.
سيكون بامكانى ان طرح كريستوفر في السجن.
These are decisions that prosecutors make every day unfettered,
هذه بعض من القرارات التي يمكن للمدعين إتخاذها كل يوم دون قيود،
and we are unaware and untrained
ونحن غير مدركين و غير مدربين
of the grave consequences of those decisions.
على ما يترتب على هذه القرارات من عواقب.
One night this past summer,
في إحدى ليالي الصيف الماضي،
I was at a small gathering of professional men of color
كنت في اجتماع صغير مع رجال من الوان مختلفة
from around the city.
من جميع أنحاء المدينة.
As I stood there stuffing free finger sandwiches into my mouth,
بينما كنت واقف هناك ادخل الساندويتشات في فمي
as you do as public servant --
كما تفعلون دائماً كموظف عمومي
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I noticed across the room,
لاحظت في الغرفه،
a young man waving and smiling at me and approaching me.
رجل شاب يبتسم لي ومن ثم اقترب مني.
And I recognized him, but I couldn't place from where,
وتعرفت عليه ولكن لم أذكر تماماً من أين
and before I knew it, this young man was hugging me.
و قبل ان ادرك كان يحتضنني
And thanking me.
ويشكرني.
"You cared about me, and you changed my life."
"إهتممت لأمري وغيرت حياتي"
It was Christopher.
لقد كان كريستوفر.
See, I never arraigned Christopher.
انظرو لم استدعي كريستوفر
He never faced a judge or a jail,
لم يواجه قاض او السجن،
he never had a criminal record.
ولم أُسجل عليه تاريخ إجرامي.
Instead, I worked with Christopher;
بدلاً من ذلك، عملت معه
first on being accountable for his actions,
بدايةً على كونه مسؤول عن أفعاله
and then, putting him in a position where he wouldn't re-offend.
وثانياً تعهده على عدم التعدي مره أخرى.
We recovered 75 percent of the computers that he sold
نحن استعدنا 75 بالمئه من أجهزة الكمبيوتر التي باعها
and gave them back to Best Buy,
وأعدناها للمحل،
and came up with a financial plan
وجئنا بخطه ماليه
to repay for the computers we couldn't recover.
لتسديد أجهزة الكمبيوتر التي لم نستطيع إعادتها.
Christopher did community service.
كريستوفر عمل في خدمة المجتمع.
He wrote an essay reflecting on how this case could impact his future
وكتب مقالة حول تأثير هذه القضية على مستقبله
and that of the community.
وعلى المجتمع.
He applied to college,
قدم طلبا إلى الكلية،
he obtained financial aid,
حصل على مساعدات مالية،
and he went on to graduate from a four-year school.
وأكمل دراسته في المدرسه حتى تخرج.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
After we finished hugging, I looked at his name tag,
بعدما احتضنني كريستوفر، نظرت إلى اسمه،
to learn that Christopher was the manager of a large bank in Boston.
لأعرف بأنه أصبح مدير لأحد البنوك الكبيره في بوسطن.
Christopher had accomplished -- and making a lot more money than me --
أنجز كريستوفر-- واكتسب الكثير من المال، أكثر مني--
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
He had accomplished all of this
برع كريستوفر في كل هذا
in the six years since I had first seen him in Roxbury Court.
فقط في ست سنوات. منذ ان رايته في محكمة روكسبري
I can't take credit for Christopher's journey to success,
لم أكن وراء قصة نجاح كريستوفر،
but I certainly did my part to keep him on the path.
ولكن من المؤكد أنني فعلت جُلّ ما أستطيع لارشاده للطريق المستقيم
There are thousands of Christophers out there,
بالتأكيد هناك الأُولوف من كريستوفر،
some locked in our jails and prisons.
بعضهم في السجن،
We need thousands of prosecutors
نحن بحاجه إلى مدعيين
to recognize that and to protect them.
ليدركونهم ويحمونهم.
An employed Christopher is better for public safety than a condemned one.
كريستوفر موظف خيرٌ من كريستوفر محكوم عليه
It's a bigger win for all of us.
إنّه فوز كبير بالنسبة لنا جميعا.
In retrospect, the decision not to throw the book at Christopher
في وقت لاحق، قرار عدم رمي الكتاب في وجه كريستوفر
makes perfect sense.
قرار صائب.
When I saw him that first day in Roxbury Court,
عندما رأيته ذلك اليوم في محكمة راكسباري،
I didn't see a criminal standing there.
لم أرى مجرم مجرم يقف هناك.
I saw myself -- a young person in need of intervention.
رأيت نفسي - شاب في حاجة للتدخل
As an individual caught selling a large quantity of drugs in my late teens,
بما أنّي فرد سبق وقبض عليه وهو يبيع كميه كبيره من المخدرات في مراهقته،
I knew firsthand the power of opportunity
أدرك تماماً ما معنى فرصه ثانيه
as opposed to the wrath of the criminal justice system.
خلافاِ للغضب الشديد من قبل العداله الجنائيه.
Along the way, with the help and guidance of my district attorney,
على طول الطريق، وذلك بمساعدة وتوجيه المدعي العام في المقاطعة ببلدي،
my supervisor and judges,
مشرفي والقُضاه،
I learned the power of the prosecutor
تعلمت مسؤولية المدعي
to change lives instead of ruining them.
في تغيير الحياه بدلاً من تخريبها.
And that's how we do it in Boston.
وهذا ما نقوم به في بوسطن.
We helped a woman who was arrested for stealing groceries to feed her kids
ساعدنا امرأه قُبض عليها بتهمة سرقة محلات البقالة وذلك لإطعام أطفالها
get a job.
في الحصول على وظيفة.
Instead of putting an abused teenager in adult jail
لم نضع مراهق في سجن بالغين
for punching another teenager,
لأنه لكم مراهق أخر،
we secured mental health treatment and community supervision.
نحن أمنّا العلاج لأصحاب الأمراض العقليه وجعلهم تحت الاشراف.
A runaway girl who was arrested
فتاة هاربه الذي ألقي القبض عليها
for prostituting, to survive on the streets,
تمارس الزنا لأجل أن تعيش
needed a safe place to live and grow --
تحتاج لمكان أمن لتسكن وتكبر فيه
something we could help her with.
شيء يمكننا مساعدتها به.
I even helped a young man
لقد ساعدت كذلك رجل شاب
who was so afraid of the older gang kids showing up after school,
اكان خائفاً من عصابات الاطفال الذين يظهرون بعد المدرسة
that one morning instead of a lunchbox into his backpack,
وفي صباح أحد الأيام بدلاً من أن يضع طعام في حقيبته
he put a loaded 9-millimeter.
وضع مسدساً عيار 9 ملم
We would spend our time that we'd normally take prepping our cases
نحن نقضي الكثير من الوقت لنستعد لقضايانا
for months and months for trial down the road
نأخذ شهور وشهور لمحاكمه قرُب وقتها
by coming up with real solutions to the problems as they presented.
عن طريق التوصل لحلول حقيقيه للمشاكل كما هي معروضه.
Which is the better way to spend our time?
ماهي أفضل طريقه نقضي فيها أوقاتنا؟
How would you prefer your prosecutors to spend theirs?
كيف تريد للمدعي العام أن يقضي وقته؟
Why are we spending 80 billion dollars
لماذا ننفق 80 مليار دولار
on a prison industry that we know is failing,
على السجون في حين أننا نعلم فشلها،
when we could take that money and reallocate it into education,
بينما نستطيع أن نستفيد من المال في التعليم
into mental health treatment,
وفي علاج الأمراض النفسية،
into substance abuse treatment
و في العلاج من تعاطي المخدرات.
and to community investment so we can develop our neighborhoods?
استثمار المجتمع حتي نستطيع تطوير أحيائنا؟
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
So why should this matter to you?
إذا لماذا هذه المسألة تهمك؟
Well, one, we're spending a lot of money.
حسنا، أولاً نحن ننفق الكثير من المال.
Our money.
مالنا.
It costs 109,000 dollars in some states
يكلف 109,000 دولار في بعض الولايات
to lock up a teenager for a year,
حبس مراهق لمدة عام،
with a 60 percent chance that that person will return to the very same system.
مع احتمالية % 60 عودته لتصرفاته القديمة.
That is a terrible return on investment.
وهذه خسارة فادحة للاستثمار
Number two: it's the right thing to do.
ثانياَ، هذا هو الشيء الصحيح الذي ينبغي عمله.
If prosecutors were a part of creating the problem,
إذا كان المدعي العام جزء من المشكله ومسببها
it's incumbent on us to create a solution
فيتحتم عليه إيجاد حل
and we can do that using other disciplines
ونستطيع ذلك بإستخدام أنظمه أخرى
that have already done the data and research for us.
التي قامت بالأبحاث لنا.
And number three:
ثالثاً:
your voice and your vote can make that happen.
صوتك وتصويتك ممكن أن يصنع ذلك.
The next time there's a local district attorney's election
في المره القادمه هناك انتخابات لمدعي المنطقه
in your jurisdiction,
في كل ولايه،
ask candidates these questions.
اسئل المرشحين هذه الأسئله.
One: What are you doing to make me and my neighbors safer?
أولاً: ماذا تفعل لتجعلني وتجعل جيراني أمنين؟
Two: What data are you collecting,
ثانياً: ماهي البيانات التي تجمعها،
and how are you training your prosecutors
وكيف تدرب نفسك وتوظف هذه البيانات
to make sure that it's working?
لتتأكد أنها تعمل؟
And number three:
ثالثاً:
If it's not working for everybody,
إذا كانت غير صالحه للجميع،
what are you doing to fix it?
كيف تصلحها؟
If they can't answer the questions,
إذا لم يستطيعوا الإجابة على الأسئلة،
they shouldn't be doing the job.
هم ليسو كُفء لهذه المهنة.
Each one of you that raised your hand at the beginning of this talk
كل واحد منكم رفع يده في البداية
is a living, breathing example of the power of opportunity,
مثال حي على فعالية الفرصه الثانية،
of intervention,
وفعالية التدخل،
of support
والدعم
and of love.
والحب.
While each of you may have faced your own brand of discipline
بينما كل واحد منكم تأدّب بطريقه ما
for whatever malfeasances you committed,
جرّاء أفعاله التي اقترفها،
barely any of you needed a day in jail
نادراً أن يحتاج أيًّ منكم ليوم في السجن
to make you the people that you are today --
ليجعلكم على ما أنتم عليه اليوم
some of the greatest minds on the planet.
بعض أعظم العقول على الكوكب
Every day, thousands of times a day,
كل يوم، ألاف المرات في اليوم،
prosecutors around the United States wield power so great
المدعيين في أنحاء أمريكا يمارسون السلطه
that it can bring about catastrophe
التي من الممكن أن تجلب الكوارث
as quickly as it can bring about opportunity,
كما يمكن أن تجلب الفرص،
intervention,
والتدخلات،
support
والدعم،
and yes, even love.
والحب أيضًا
Those qualities are the hallmarks of a strong community,
وهذه السمات هي ما تجعلنا مجتمع قوي،
and a strong community is a safe one.
المجتمع القوي هو مجتمع أمن
If our communities are broken,
لو كانت مجتمعاتنا متفككه،
don't let the lawyers that you elect fix them
لا تجعلون المحاميين يصلحونها لكم
with outdated, inefficient, expensive methods.
بطرق مُكلفه وقديمه غير فعّاله.
Demand more; vote for the prosecutor who's helping people stay out of jail,
رشحو مَن مِن المُتوقع أن يبقي الناس بعيداً عن السجن،
not putting them in.
لا من يضعهم فيه.
Demand better.
طالبو بالأفضل.
You deserve it, your children deserve it,
أنتم وأطفالكم تستحقون ذلك،
the people who are tied up in the system deserve it,
الاشخاص الذين قيدوا فى النظام يستحقون ذلك،
but most of all,
ولكن الأهم من ذلك كله،
the people that we are sworn to protect and do justice for demand it.
والشعب الذي أقسمنا أن نحميه يستحق ذلك.
We must,
نحن يجب،
we must do better.
يجب أن نُنَفّذ الأفضل.
Thank you.
شكرا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thank you very much.
شكراً جزيلاً.